John Gregory Bourke papers, 1873-1897
University of Arizona Libraries, Special Collections
John Gregory Bourke papers, 1873-1897
AZ 347
This collection includes correspondence, including letters from Gen. George Crook recommending Bourke for promotions, letters from publishers, and others to and from Bourke relating to his writing and military experiences.
Bourke, John Gregory, 1846-1896
15 items
University of Arizona Libraries, Special Collections University of Arizona PO Box 210055 Tucson, AZ 85721-0055 Phone: 520-621-6423 Fax: 520-621-9733 URL: http://speccoll.library.arizona.edu/
Restrictions
None.
Biographical Note
John Gregory Bourke was a U.S. Army soldier, ethnologist, and author.
Scope and Content Note
This collection includes correspondence, including letters from Gen. George Crook recommending Bourke for promotions, letters from publishers, and others to and from Bourke relating to his writing and military experiences.
Access Terms
Bourke, John Gregory, 1846-1896 -- Correspondence
Crook, George, 1829-1890 -- Correspondence
Correspondence
Container List
- General George Crook: Generals Orders no. 14. Typewritten, regarding 2nd Lt. John Bourke and the Apache Campaign, Prescott, Arizona Territory. April 9, 1873 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- General George Crook to Secretary of War: Typewritten recommendation of Bourke for appointment to Inspector General's Corps, Whipple Barracks, Arizona Territory. March 15, 1885 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- E. A. Snow to President of the United States, Grover Cleveland: Typewritten recommendation of Bourke for appointment to Inspector General's Corps, Washington, D. C. January 17, 1888 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- General George Crook to President of the United States, Grover Cleveland: Typewritten recommendation of Bourke as Major and Inspector General, Omaha, Nebraska. January 24, 1888 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- General George Crook to Bourke's daughter: "Warmest thanks for your kind congratulations and wishes," etc., Omaha, Nebraska. April 15, 1888 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- John Bourke and W. H. Lowdermilk & Co.: Agreement regarding selling of "Scatalogic Rites of All Nations" at $3.50, Washington D. C. March 6 1891 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- W. C. Brownell of Scribner's Sons to John Bourke: Regarding distribution of copies of On the Border with Crook, New York. December 9, 1891 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- W. W. Rockhill to John Bourke: Regarding Bourke's responsibility for the exhibit "La Rabida" at the World's Columbian Exposition, Chicago? September 4, 1893 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Hamlin Russell of the St. Louis Chronicle to John Bourke: Regarding past military experiences together and the death of a mutual friend and officer, St. Louis, Missouri. January 19, 1894 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Author John Hittell to John Bourke: Comments on Bourke's writings and his own, San Francisco. April 22, 1894 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Author Thomas H. Wilson to John Bourke: Request for information about the Arizona campaign, Ft. Omaha, Nebraska. November 30, 1894 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- John Bourke to Adjutant General, U. S. A.: Request for copies of history books for information to help in military situations, Ft. Ethan Allen, Vermont. Request denied on verso. June 12, 1895 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- John ? to Bourke's wife (?): Regarding a forthcoming visit and his own wife's illness, Philadelphia. December 6, 1897 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- T. H. Stanton to Mrs. Bourke: Regarding an unidentified book. No date (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Partially completed voucher, signed by Bourke. (Box 1, Folder 1)